【The fate that cannot be liberated】
[해방될 수 없는 운명]
[Episode 23]
[23화]
Why do you think bandits have anything to do with me?
왜 도적들이 나와 관련이 있다고 생각합니까 ?
Someone ambushed you on the hunting grounds.
누군가 사냥터에서 당신을 매복 공격했습니다.
This never happened.
이런 일은 결코 일어나지 않았습니다.
Does it also have something to do with me?
그것도 나와 관련이 있는 걸까?
You know everyone in this palace, except Wang Dequan,
당신은 왕덕취(王德泉)를 제외하고 이 궁전에 있는 모든 사람을 알고 있습니다 .
He is an old servant of the former emperor.
그는 전 황제의 늙은 신하이다.
The rest is all brought by you.
나머지는 모두 고객님께서 가져오셨습니다.
How did I pull them off?
내가 어떻게 그것들을 떼어냈나요?
No one knows?
아무도 모른다?
What about military tokens?
군사 토큰은 어떻습니까?
since you became regent
네가 섭정이 된 이후로
The He family was wiped out.
He 가족은 전멸되었습니다.
The Yan family was sent to Sichuan
Yan 가족은 쓰촨으로 파견되었습니다.
After the hunt.
사냥 후.
Which of them doesn't want it?
그들 중 누가 그것을 원하지 않습니까?
Why do you think it's me?
왜 나인 것 같아?
You are my uncle.
당신은 나의 삼촌입니다.
Your Majesty, there is no need to quibble.
폐하, 불평할 필요가 없습니다.
But you should know about the He family.
하지만 당신은 He 가족에 대해 알아야 합니다.
I'm more concerned about
내가 더 걱정되는 건
These are dangerous and unpredictable situations.
이는 위험하고 예측할 수 없는 상황입니다.
Do you admit it?
인정하시나요?
Did you frame the entire He family?
He 가족 전체를 모함했습니까?
Your Majesty has been in poor health recently.
폐하께서는 최근 건강이 좋지 않으셨습니다.
Rest in the palace from now on.
이제부터 궁전에서 쉬세요.
You don't need to worry about anything else.
다른 것에 대해 걱정할 필요가 없습니다.
Do you want to put me under house arrest?
나를 가택연금시키시겠어요?
No.
아니요.
I just
난 그냥
Try sharing your concerns.
고민을 공유해 보세요.
How...how dare you?
어떻게... 어떻게 감히?
guard!
경비원!
Where are the guards?
경비원은 어디에 있습니까?
You bastard!
이 개자식!
Your Majesty,
폐하,
Do you know how to curse now?
이제 욕하는 법을 아시나요?
I'm too kind.
나는 너무 친절하다.
I convinced the bird that it had strong wings.
나는 그 새에게 강한 날개가 있다고 확신시켰습니다.
Since you think you are an eagle, I will put you in a cage
네가 독수리라고 생각하니 새장에 넣어줄게
so you know
그러니까 너도 알잖아
You are just a caged bird.
당신은 단지 우리에 갇힌 새일 뿐입니다.
Rong Yu,
유 롱,
You said I'm not the person you're destined to be
당신은 내가 당신이 될 사람이 아니라고 말했어요
And I am not on your marriage line.
그리고 나는 당신의 결혼 라인에 있지 않습니다.
So why no matter how we wander
그러니 우리가 아무리 방황해도 왜
Even if we are thousands of miles apart,
우리가 수천 마일 떨어져 있어도
I still married you
난 아직 너랑 결혼했어
And fell in love with you?
그리고 당신과 사랑에 빠졌나요?
Isn't this fate?
이것이 운명이 아닌가?
I can't imagine that future
그런 미래는 상상할 수 없어
With anyone but you.
너 말고 누구랑도.
Just be a general.
그냥 장군이 되세요.
The future General Rong.
미래의 롱 장군.
Your General Xiaorong.
샤오롱 장군님.
What if she was a girl?
만약 그녀가 여자였다면?
We will pamper her to no end.
우리는 그녀를 끝까지 애지중지할 것입니다.
Not to mention ten years, not even a day,
10년은 말할 것도 없고 하루도 아닌데
Do we want her to leave us and go to Mount Wuhua to suffer?
그녀가 우리를 떠나 우화산으로 가서 고통받기를 바라나요?
Thinking of our General Xiaorong or Miss Xiaorong
우리 샤오롱 장군 이나 샤오롱 선생님을 생각하며
Let my heart sing.
내 마음이 노래하게 해주세요.
Usually, it's you who runs to me.
보통 나한테 달려오는 건 너야.
Can I finally contact you this time?
이번에 드디어 연락해도 될까요 ?
Normally, I don't give people second chances.
일반적으로 나는 사람들에게 두 번째 기회를 주지 않습니다 .
But for you, I am willing to give countless opportunities.
하지만 나는 당신에게 셀 수 없이 많은 기회를 주고 싶습니다.
I've run to you.
나는 당신에게 달려갔습니다.
if you still love me
아직도 나를 사랑한다면
Just stretch out your hand,
손을 뻗어보세요.
I am willing to give you all my love
나는 당신에게 내 사랑을 모두 줄 의향이 있습니다
And sincerity for the rest of my life.
그리고 평생 성실함.
What if I told you
내가 만약 네게 말했다면
I do not like you anymore?
나는 더 이상 너를 좋아하지 않아?
Then why did you rush into the fire to save me?
그런데 왜 나를 구하려고 불 속으로 달려가셨나요?
The fire was so intense.
불이 너무 강렬했어요.
I can't even escape myself.
나 자신도 벗어날 수 없습니다.
Why did you do that?
왜 그런 짓을 한거야?
I will save anyone without hesitation
누구라도 서슴없이 구해내겠어
Inside the Astrology Hall.
점성술 홀 내부.
I can't stand idly by
가만히 있을 수가 없어
And watching someone die in front of me.
그리고 내 앞에서 누군가 죽는 걸 지켜보는 거죠.
but…
하지만…
Since you are so upright and noble,
당신은 너무나 올바르고 고귀하기 때문에,
why are you going to all this trouble
왜 이런 문제를 일으키려고 합니까?
Eliminate everyone who is harmful to me?
나에게 해로운 사람을 모두 제거하시겠습니까?
All I did was help the emperor
내가 한 일은 황제를 도운 것 뿐이었어
Destroy the bad guys as quickly as possible.
가능한 한 빨리 나쁜 놈들을 파괴하십시오.
I didn't think too much about it.
나는 그것에 대해 너무 많이 생각하지 않았습니다.
School is out! School is out!
학교가 나왔습니다! 학교가 나왔습니다!
Master, I want to pray for Xingxiang Pavilion tonight.
스승님, 오늘 밤 저는 싱샹루(Xingxiang Pavilion)를 위해 기도하고 싶습니다 .
Can you tell me what to say?
무슨 말을 해야 할지 말해줄 수 있나요?
OK Go play.
좋아요 가서 놀아요.
Thank you Master.
감사합니다 선생님.
let's go. Let's go play together.
갑시다. 같이 놀러 가자.
OK
좋아요
When I'm sick and confused,
내가 아프고 혼란스러울 때,
I only recognized you.
나는 당신만을 인식했습니다.
That will definitely give you false hope,
그것은 분명히 당신에게 거짓된 희망을 줄 것입니다.
But this is just an illusion.
그러나 이것은 단지 환상일 뿐이다.
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
why do you think
왜 그렇게 생각하니?
i will still love you
나는 여전히 당신을 사랑합니다
After knowing that you burned down my Xingxiang Pavilion?
당신이 내 Xingxiang Pavilion을 불태운 것을 알고 나면?
Did Madam run to put out the fire?
부인은 불을 끄려고 달려갔나요?
that's right.
좋아요.
correct?
옳은?
Your Highness, the Emperor is not having an easy time right now.
폐하, 황제폐하께서 지금은 편한 시간을 보내지 않으십니다.
As Jialin’s mainstay,
Jialin의 주력으로서,
Please give me more guidance in the future.
앞으로도 많은 지도 부탁드립니다.
please.
제발.
——Master, the young master is back! - This is…
——스승님, 젊은 스승님이 돌아왔습니다! - 이것은…
minute.
분.
Father.
아버지.
what happened?
무슨 일이에요?
Master Rong said I won’t see you again.
롱스님은 다시는 만나지 않겠다고 하셨습니다.
All these things are yours.
이 모든 것이 당신 것입니다.
You can take them away.
당신은 그들을 가져갈 수 있습니다.
If you don't want them, I'll have them thrown away.
원치 않으시면 버리도록 하겠습니다.
Zhanping.
잔핑.
I -
나 -
Stop talking.
말을 중지하세요.
I don't know how to face you now.
나는 이제 당신을 어떻게 대해야 할지 모르겠습니다.
Teacher Rong is so kind to you.
Rong 선생님은 당신에게 매우 친절합니다.
Why do you want to hurt him like this?
왜 그 사람을 이렇게 다치게 하려는 걸까요?
If you are going through something, you can tell us.
어떤 일을 겪고 계시다면 저희에게 말씀해 주세요.
Do you know how important Xingxiang Pavilion is to him?
Xingxiang Pavilion이 그에게 얼마나 중요한지 아십니까 ?
forget it.
잊어 버려.
This is the money Master Rong has prepared for you. You should leave.
이것은 롱 선생님이 당신을 위해 준비한 돈입니다. 당신은 떠나야합니다.
No.
아니요.
Does he have any other news for me?
그 사람이 나에게 전할 다른 소식이 있나요?
nothing.
아무것도 아님.
You should leave. If you don't, I'll have to kick you out.
당신은 떠나야합니다. 안 그러면 쫓아내야 해요.
Stop pretending. It doesn't work.
척하지 마세요. 작동하지 않습니다.
Master Rong and I will never trust you again.
Rong 선생님과 저는 다시는 당신을 믿지 않을 것입니다.
I understand.
이해합니다.
Then tell him to take care.
그런 다음 그에게 조심하라고 말하세요.
I won't bother him anymore.
나는 더 이상 그를 괴롭히지 않을 것입니다.
Don't say these hypocritical things.
이런 위선적인 말을 하지 마세요.
You are the worst person ever. Let's go.
당신은 역대 최악의 사람입니다. 갑시다.
Xunxunan humiliates us like this.
Xunxunan은 우리를 이렇게 모욕합니다.
My sister is still waiting for us to rescue her.
내 여동생은 아직도 우리가 그녀를 구출해주기를 기다리고 있다.
Father, please raise an army.
아버지, 군대를 키워주세요.
nonsense!
무의미한 말!
How could you start a war so hastily?
어떻게 그렇게 성급하게 전쟁을 시작할 수 있었나요?
This is a blatant provocation.
이것은 노골적인 도발이다.
Should we just let Ren Yinxiao be rude?
Ren Yinxiao가 무례하게 행동하도록 놔둬야 할까요?
Do you want your sister to die in a foreign country?
언니가 외국에서 죽기를 바라나요?
when i leave,
내가 떠날 때,
My sister is still locked in that useless prince's yard.
내 여동생은 아직도 그 쓸모없는 왕자의 마당 에 갇혀있습니다 .
She couldn't even get a decent meal.
그녀는 제대로 된 식사조차 할 수 없었습니다.
If we don't act quickly,
빨리 조치하지 않으면,
We may have to collect her body, father.
시신을 수습해야 할 수도 있어요, 아버지.
I…
나…
I wrote a letter to Ren Yinxiao.
나는 Ren Yinxiao에게 편지를 썼습니다.
What good does this letter do?
이 편지가 무슨 소용이 있나요?
It was obvious they were not afraid of us.
그들은 우리를 두려워하지 않는 것이 분명했습니다.
Otherwise, they would not make such a move.
그렇지 않으면 그들은 그러한 조치를 취하지 않을 것입니다.
Do you know what conscription means?
징병이 무슨 뜻인지 아시나요?
Do you know what preparations are needed for war?
전쟁을 위해서는 어떤 준비가 필요한지 아시나요 ?
War is a conflict between two sides
전쟁은 양측의 갈등이다
We can't just jump in just because of one person.
단지 한 사람 때문에 뛰어들 수는 없습니다 .
But - but she's your daughter.
하지만 - 하지만 그 사람은 당신 딸이에요.
She is also my sister.
그녀는 또한 나의 여동생이다.
She was given the title of princess.
그녀에게는 공주라는 칭호가 주어졌습니다.
She now represents Jia Lin.
그녀는 이제 Jia Lin을 대표합니다.
what do you know
당신은 무엇을 알 수 있습니까
Diplomatic and court affairs?
외교 및 법원 업무?
you are right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
i don't know anything about it
나는 그것에 대해 아무것도 모른다
But I know you're afraid.
하지만 나는 당신이 두려워한다는 것을 압니다.
before you do anything,
무슨 일을 하기 전에,
You always go to Xingxiang Pavilion to ask Rong Gong.
당신은 항상 Xingxiang Pavilion에 가서 Rong Gong에게 물어 봅니다.
You are always cautious, timid, and careful.
당신은 항상 조심스럽고 소심하며 조심스럽습니다.
How can you achieve something significant?
어떻게 중요한 일을 성취할 수 있습니까?
you…
너…
anything else?
다른 건 없어?
This is enough.
이것으로 충분합니다.
OK
좋아요
Are you blind?
당신은 장님입니까?
Now you even dare to bully me?
이제 네가 감히 나를 괴롭힐 셈이냐?
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
what happened?
무슨 일이에요?
You don't hate me now.
이제 당신은 나를 미워하지 않습니다.
I do.
그래요.
It's just that I'm not in the mood right now.
단지 지금은 기분이 좋지 않아서일 뿐입니다.
He Jiuling,
허 지울링,
I have something to tell you.
당신에게 말할 게 있어요.
I don't believe a word you said.
나는 당신이 한 말을 하나도 믿지 않습니다.
King Xunnan is not that kind of person.
Xunnan 왕은 그런 사람이 아닙니다.
How do you know he's not like that?
그 사람이 그렇지 않다는 것을 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
If you slander others again
또 다른 사람을 비방한다면
I'll teach you a lesson.
제가 한 수 가르쳐 드리겠습니다.
I just remembered...
방금 생각났는데...
gentlemen.
신사.
You two are old acquaintances, aren't you?
너희 둘은 오랜 친구지, 그렇지 않니?
When I was still Prince Yong,
내가 아직 영세자였을 때,
He even proposed in the palace.
그는 심지어 궁전에서 프로포즈도 했습니다.
Although he failed to marry you,
비록 그 사람이 당신과 결혼하는데 실패했지만,
You two are at least friends.
너희 둘은 적어도 친구야.
He is really lucky.
그는 정말 운이 좋다.
He Jiuling,
허 지울링,
Now there is no one to help my sister.
이제 내 여동생을 도와줄 사람은 아무도 없어요.
can you help me if possible
가능하다면 저를 도와주실 수 있나요?
To save my sister?
내 여동생을 구하기 위해서?
Sit here and make tea for you
여기 앉아서 차를 끓여주세요
It was through gnashing of teeth.
이를 갈면서였습니다.
How dare you embarrass Miss He?
어떻게 감히 Miss He를 당황하게 만들 수 있나요?
Here you go, sir.
여기요, 선생님.
- sorry. - please.
- 죄송합니다. - 제발.
Before, my sister and I
예전에는 언니랑 나랑
Did a lot of bad things to you.
당신에게 나쁜 짓을 많이 했어요.
I always feel sorry.
나는 항상 미안함을 느낀다.
I sincerely apologize and will do my best
진심으로 사과드리며 최선을 다하겠습니다
To make it up to you.
당신에게 달려있습니다.
Apologize?
사과하다?
Do you really think apologizing can solve everything?
정말 사과하면 모든 것이 해결될 수 있다고 생각하시나요 ?
Stop pretending you don't know what's going on here.
여기서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지 모르는 척하지 마세요 .
Tan.
탠 껍질.
I can write to you to ask about the situation,
상황에 대해 물어보려고 편지를 쓸 수도 있고 ,
But there is nothing I can do.
하지만 내가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없습니다.
even so,
비록 그렇다 하더라도,
You are the only one who can help me.
당신은 나를 도울 수 있는 유일한 사람입니다.
My apology just now was sincere.
방금 제가 한 사과는 진심이었습니다.
From the bottom of my heart.
진심으로.
If you need my help in the future
앞으로 내 도움이 필요하다면
with anything,
무엇이든,
Even help you reverse the case,
사건을 뒤집는 데 도움을 주기도 하고,
You can come to me anytime.
언제든지 나에게 올 수 있습니다.
unnecessary.
불필요한.
No.
아니요.
I will always remember this in my heart.
나는 이것을 항상 마음 속에 기억할 것입니다.
You and Rong Yu are
당신과 Rong Yu는
Much like now.
지금과 매우 비슷합니다.
If it were you before
예전에 너였다면
You would have laughed before
예전에는 웃었을 텐데
And scolded me
그리고 나를 꾸짖었다.
For those in this situation,
이런 상황에 처한 분들을 위해,
but now you want
하지만 지금 당신은 원해요
sit with people you don't like
싫어하는 사람이랑 같이 앉아
Even invited me to tea.
심지어 나를 차에 초대했습니다.
Although I hate to admit it,
인정하기 싫지만,
You and Rong Yu are actually a good match.
당신과 Rong Yu는 실제로 좋은 짝입니다.
What a fool.
정말 바보 로군.
Do you intentionally make others angry?
당신은 의도적으로 다른 사람을 화나게 합니까?
Jiuling, let’s go.
지울링, 가자.
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
Can I…
내가…
can i be your friend?
내가 너의 친구가 될 수 있을까?
We will never be friends.
우리는 결코 친구가 될 수 없습니다.
go out! You all go out.
나가! 여러분 모두 나가세요.
Cheng'an, it's me.
청안, 나야.
Cheng'an.
청안.
elder sister.
언니.
I know you'll be fine.
나는 당신이 괜찮을 거라는 걸 알아요.
Cheng'an, I'm not just good at
청안아, 난 잘하는 것만이 아니야
Pray to Bodhisattva for help.
보살에게 도움을 청하세요.
Believe me.
나를 믿어.
In times of crisis,
위기의 시대에는,
I can protect you too.
나도 당신을 보호할 수 있어요.
[Jiang's Mansion]
[장씨의 저택]
You lied to me, right?
나한테 거짓말한 거 맞지?
Things about the He family,
He 가족에 관한 것들,
It has nothing to do with our family, right?
우리 가족과는 아무 상관도 없잖아요?
Otherwise, how could I not know anything?
그렇지 않으면 내가 어찌 아무것도 모를 수 있겠습니까?
For such things,
그런 것들에 대해서는,
Do I need to tell you loud and clear?
큰 소리로 명확하게 말해야 합니까?
What now?
지금은 무엇입니까?
Why are you telling me all this now?
왜 지금 나한테 그런 얘기를 하는 거야?
if you don't want me to know
내가 알기 싫다면
Why can't you hide it from me forever?
왜 영원히 나에게 숨길 수 없나요?
Because in the future,
왜냐하면 앞으로도,
person sitting on the throne
왕좌에 앉은 사람
It will be you.
당신이 될 것입니다.
How could you say such rebellious words?
어떻게 그런 반항적인 말을 할 수 있었나요?
Isn't your current position strong enough?
당신의 현재 위치는 충분히 강하지 않습니까?
Min, this is not a question of whether it is enough.
민, 이건 충분하느냐의 문제가 아니다 .
If I hadn’t gotten rid of the Nanjiang He family back then,
그때 내가 난장화씨 가문을 없애지 않았더라면,
Will our family still have its current status?
우리 가족은 여전히 ​​현재 상태를 유지합니까?
If I don't stand at the highest position now,
지금 내가 가장 높은 자리에 서지 못한다면
Is there any way out for our family?
우리 가족을 위한 탈출구는 없을까?
Min, it's time for you to know.
민, 이제 당신이 알아야 할 시간이에요.
I don't want to hear these words from you.
나는 당신에게서 이런 말을 듣고 싶지 않습니다.
I only know that when the He family is here,
나는 단지 He 가족이 여기에 있을 때,
Our lives are just as beautiful.
우리의 삶도 그만큼 아름답습니다.
Why do you have to reach such great heights?
왜 그렇게 큰 높이에 도달해야합니까?
What now?
지금은 무엇입니까?
Shouldn't the most important thing now be to rescue my sister?
이제 가장 중요한 일은 내 여동생을 구출하는 일이 아닐까?
My sister is still waiting for us to rescue her.
내 여동생은 아직도 우리가 그녀를 구출해주기를 기다리고 있다.
Now is the moment of truth.
지금은 진실의 순간이다.
I won't allow anyone or anything to ruin my plans.
나는 누구도, 어떤 것도 내 계획을 망치는 것을 허용하지 않을 것입니다 .
Not even your sister.
네 여동생도 아니야.
So, you mean
그러니까, 당신 말은
You only care about your future and goals,
당신은 미래와 목표에만 관심이 있습니다.
You and my sister get along very well
당신과 내 여동생은 아주 잘 지내요
Being bullied and self-destructing in Xunnan?
Xunnan에서 괴롭힘을 당하고 자멸하고 있습니까?
After a while, I'll figure it out.
시간이 좀 지나서 알아볼게요.
So do you really want to do this?
그럼 정말로 이 일을 하시겠습니까?
I can not believe it,
믿을 수 없어,
At this time, my closest family members are actually
현재 나의 가장 가까운 가족은 실제로
More indifferent than the people I’ve hurt?
내가 상처받은 사람들보다 더 무관심한가?
Stop there.
거기 멈춰라.
Do you think I don't worry or care about Lin?
내가 린에 대해 걱정하지도 신경 쓰지도 않을 것 같나요?
There is no turning back.
되돌릴 수 없습니다.
Min, you don't want to destroy our whole family, do you?
민, 당신은 우리 가족 전체를 파괴하고 싶지 않습니까 ?
I have no idea.
나는 모른다.
I do not know anything.
나는 아무것도 모른다.
I just wish you hadn't told me all this today.
오늘은 네가 나한테 이 모든 걸 말하지 않았으면 좋았을 텐데.
- minute. - Stop pushing me, Father.
- 분. - 그만 밀어내세요, 신부님.
a stranger.
낯선 사람.
Princess of Zealand.
뉴질랜드의 공주.
General He.
장군 그.
Lord Jiuling.
지울링님.
【Guozi Studies】
【국자학】
——He Jiuling. - Your Majesty.
——그 Jiuling. - 폐하.
hurry up. We may be discovered soon.
서둘러요. 우리는 곧 발견될 수도 있습니다.
Jiuling, I…
지울링, 나…
assassin!
암살자!
You go first, I'll stay behind. go!
당신이 먼저 가세요, 나는 뒤에 있을게요. 가다!
- go. - There are assassins!
- 가다. - 암살자가 있어요!
Master Rong.
롱 선생님.
Zhanping.
잔핑.
What's wrong?
뭐가 문제 야?
Prepare your horses to fight against General Yan.
Yan 장군과 싸울 말을 준비하세요.
Let go of the emperor!
황제를 놓아주세요!
You all go!
모두 가세요!
He-He Jiuling.
히헤지울링.
move.
이동하다.
Has it always been you?
항상 당신이었나요?
The palace was crowded with our people.
궁전은 우리 국민으로 붐볐습니다.
There is no way you can escape.
탈출할 수 있는 방법은 없습니다.
You are asking for death.
당신은 죽음을 요구하고 있습니다.
We'll wait and see
우리는 기다려 볼 것이다
Who will bear the consequences.
그 결과는 누가 감당할 것인가?
He Jiuling, you'll die.
He Jiuling, 당신은 죽을 것입니다.
Rebellious.
반항적이다.
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
How dare you traitors kidnap His Majesty.
감히 반역자들이 폐하를 납치하는 것이 가능합니다.
He Jiuling asked them to put down their weapons quickly.
He Jiuling은 그들에게 빨리 무기를 내려놓으라고 요청했습니다 .
I will beg my father to spare your life.
나는 아버지께 당신의 생명을 살려달라고 간청하겠습니다.
Jiuling.
지울링.
Your Majesty,
폐하,
We need to wait.
우리는 기다려야 합니다.
He Jiuling, I beg you.
그는 Jiuling, 간청합니다.
Are you still insisting?
아직도 고집하고 있나요?
Kill them all.
그들 모두를 죽일.
- stop. - No.
- 멈추다. - 아니요.
His Majesty is still among them.
폐하께서는 아직도 그들 가운데 계십니다.
shooting.
촬영.
stop. Everyone stop.
멈추다. 다들 멈춰요.
Jiuling.
지울링.
About the He family,
He 가족에 대해,
I asked my father.
나는 아버지에게 물었다.
I'm very sorry.
나는 매우 미안 해요.
I can't do anything for you.
나는 당신을 위해 아무것도 할 수 없습니다.
I…
나…
If I…
만약 내가…
I knew it very early,
아주 일찍 알았지만,
I would have stopped my father.
나는 아버지를 막았을 것입니다.
If this had never happened,
이런 일이 일어나지 않았다면,
we can…
우리는 할 수 있습니다…
Can we be friends?
우리 친구가 될 수 있을까?
You'd better not tell me the answer.
나에게 대답을 말하지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
Because next time,
왜냐면 다음에는
I will definitely do better
난 분명 더 잘할 거야
Compare…
비교하다…
Master Biron,
마스터 비론,
or even better
아니면 더 나은
than anyone else.
누구보다.
He Jiuling,
허 지울링,
I like you.
좋아해요.
minute.
분.
Lord Zhongyong. Lord Zhongyong.
중용공주.중용공.
Chengyuan three years
청원 3년
Jiang Hesen, the loyal Lord of Yong, created chaos in the palace and attempted to murder the emperor.
충직한 용왕 강화삼은 궁궐을 혼란에 빠뜨리고 황제를 살해하려 했습니다.
Now arrest his accomplices. Minister of Justice Wang Tongren.
이제 공범자들을 체포하세요. 왕퉁런 법무부 장관.
Li Mu, Minister of Rites.
리무(Li Mu) 의례부 장관.
Imperial Academy Scholars Zhao Zhen and Jiang Shengtian.
제국 아카데미 학자 Zhao Zhen과 Jiang Shengtian.
Those who disobey will be summarily executed.
불순종하는 자는 즉결 처형될 것이다.
By order of the emperor, Jiang Hesen was deprived of his title...
황제의 명령에 따라 장화센은 직함을 박탈당했습니다.
minute.
분.
He will be executed at Liudaokou at noon
그는 정오에 육도구에서 처형될 것이다
Give everyone a warning and an example.
모든 사람에게 경고 와 모범을 보여주십시오.
Investigation reveals General He Liang
조사 결과 허량 (He Liang) 장군이 밝혀졌다
He was framed by a traitor for colluding with the enemy.
그는 적과 공모했다는 이유로 배신자에게 누명을 썼습니다.
Now restored to the position of General He Liang
이제 He Liang 장군의 지위로 복귀되었습니다.
And was awarded the lofty title of Protector of the Country.
그리고 국가 수호자라는 고귀한 칭호를 받았습니다.
Now I only have one thing to ask for, the Emperor's favor.
이제 내가 바라는 것은 단 하나, 황제의 은총뿐이다.
what is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Can my merits offset the past mistakes of Jiang Rong and Xingxiang Pavilion?
내 장점이 Jiang Rong과 Xingxiang Pavilion의 과거 실수를 상쇄할 수 있습니까?
He Chenzhou was reinstated as military supervisor.
He Chenzhou는 군 감독관으로 복직되었습니다 .
His wife was given the title of second-class lady and a title of nobility.
그의 아내는 이등부인이라는 칭호와 귀족이라는 칭호를 받았습니다.
[The Tomb of General He Liang] He Qingxing was restored as the internal general.
[하량장군릉] 허청싱이 내장으로 복위되었다.
His wife was given the title of third-grade lady and a title of nobility.
그의 아내는 3급 귀부인이라는 칭호와 귀족이라는 칭호를 받았습니다 .
Promote it to the world and make it known to everyone.
이를 세상에 널리 알리고 모든 사람에게 알리십시오.
[The Tomb of General He Liang]
[허량장군 묘]
Our He family
우리 그 가족
The grievances have been redressed.
불만 사항이 해결되었습니다.
【Astrology Center】
【점성술 센터】
I am preparing to choose the next owner of Xingxiang Pavilion.
저는 Xingxiang Pavilion의 다음 소유자를 선택할 준비를 하고 있습니다.
Master, we should take our time.
선생님, 시간을 좀 가져보겠습니다.
There is no need to be so hasty in choosing a successor.
후임자를 선택하는 데 너무 성급할 필요는 없습니다.
We have to prepare for the Astrology Festival
우리는 점성술 축제를 준비해야 해요
And also need to improve our divination tutorial.
그리고 점술 튜토리얼 도 개선해야 합니다 .
We need to recruit new fortune tellers.
새로운 점쟁이를 모집해야 합니다.
There is a lot to do.
할 것이 많다.
We don't want to rush things.
우리는 일을 서두르고 싶지 않습니다.
And just like Astrology Day, there’s no need to find someone else to take over.
그리고 점성술의 날과 마찬가지로, 대신 할 다른 사람을 찾을 필요가 없습니다.
others may think
다른 사람들은 생각할 수도 있다
Master has left us.
스승님은 우리를 떠났습니다.
Yes Master.
알겠습니다.
Your Majesty.
폐하.
[Xuanzheng Hall]
[쉬안정 홀]
Looking south to attack. Nanjiang is in urgent need of help.
남쪽을 바라보며 공격합니다. 난장(南江)에는 긴급 도움이 필요합니다.
We lost Fanzhou.
우리는 Fanzhou를 잃었습니다.
All 30,000 soldiers in Wutu City were killed.
Wutu City의 군인 30,000명이 모두 사망했습니다.
There are no soldiers of the Chen family guarding the city.
도시를 지키는 첸 가문의 군인은 없습니다.
What did you say. ?
뭐라고 하셨나요. ?
You are so reckless.
당신은 너무 무모합니다.
That's not right.
그건 맞지 않습니다.
You are wrong.
당신은 잘못.
How could you do this?
어떻게 이런 일을 할 수 있었나요?
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
How could this happen?
어떻게 이런 일이 일어날 수 있습니까?
Why did Xunnan attack Jialin?
Xunnan은 왜 Jialin을 공격했습니까?
Senior brother must have been manipulated.
형이 조작됐나 봐요 .
I must find him.
그를 찾아야 해요.
Don't be impulsive.
충동적이지 마십시오.
Even if he is controlled,
통제당한다 해도,
What can you do yourself?
스스로 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
And if your senior brother really wants to attack Jialin,
그리고 만약 당신의 형이 정말로 Jialin을 공격하고 싶다면,
What can you do about this?
이에 대해 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
I will lead the troops myself.
내가 직접 군대를 지휘하겠습니다.
Your Majesty, please don't.
폐하, 그러지 마십시오.
never.
절대.
Your Majesty, you cannot do this.
폐하, 이러시면 안 됩니다.
Your Majesty, please think again.
폐하, 다시 생각해 보십시오.
The royal family is now in decline.
이제 왕실은 쇠퇴하고 있습니다.
As soon as His Majesty leaves, the family forest will have no roots.
폐하께서 떠나시면 가족의 숲에는 뿌리가 없을 것입니다.
There will be no one to defend the capital.
수도를 방어할 사람은 아무도 없을 것입니다.
It is difficult to avoid the situation of the previous regent.
이전 섭정의 상황을 피하기는 어렵습니다 .
Yes, Your Majesty.
예, 폐하.
Your Majesty, please think again.
폐하, 다시 생각해 보십시오.
So, who do you think can go to Nanjiang?
그럼 누가 난장(Nanjiang)에 갈 수 있다고 생각하시나요?
TT-This…
TT-이건…
Jialin has just calmed down the internal conflicts.
Jialin은 내부 갈등을 진정시켰습니다.
Then Xunnan has ulterior motives.
그렇다면 Xunnan은 은밀한 동기를 가지고 있습니다.
I cannot protect General Zuo from being destroyed.
나는 Zuo 장군이 멸망되는 것을 막을 수 없습니다.
Do I have to look at my right general too?
내 오른쪽 장군도 봐야 하나?
and thousands of soldiers
그리고 수천명의 군인들
He died in Nanjiang and could not return to his hometown?
남강(南江)에서 죽어 고향으로 돌아가지 못하였다고?
Your Majesty, I have to say something disrespectful.
폐하, 무례한 말씀을 드리고 싶습니다.
Even if you lead the troops yourself, what can you do?
당신이 직접 군대를 지휘한다고 해도 당신은 무엇을 할 수 있는가?
Our best Jialin commanders have already arrived in Nanjiang.
우리 최고의 가림 사령관들이 이미 난장에 도착했습니다.
The best men had been exterminated by the regent.
최고의 인물들은 섭정에 의해 몰살당했습니다.
If there was no commander like He Liang to lead the troops to kill the enemy,
만약 허량처럼 군대를 이끌고 적을 죽이는 지휘관이 없었다면 ,
it's no use.
그것은 소용이 없습니다.
I think it's better to send someone to negotiate with Xunnan as soon as possible.
가능한 한 빨리 Xunnan과 협상할 사람을 보내는 것이 더 낫다고 생각합니다.
Strive to minimize losses at the minimum cost.
최소한의 비용으로 손실을 최소화하도록 노력합니다.
Your Majesty.
폐하.
Without commanders like my father and brothers,
아버지와 형제 같은 지휘관이 없으면
I don't know if I can fight for His Majesty.
제가 폐하를 위해 싸울 수 있을지 모르겠습니다.
TT-This…
TT-이건…
This is ridiculous.
이건 말도 안 돼요.
She is just a little commander. How could she take on such responsibility?
그녀는 단지 작은 사령관입니다. 그녀가 어떻게 그런 책임을 질 수 있었습니까?
Apart from,
와는 별개로,
She and Ren Yinxiao are friends.
그녀와 Ren Yinxiao는 친구입니다.
When they were in Nanjiang, they often communicated with each other.
난장(南江)에 있을 때 그들은 서로 자주 연락을 주고받았다.
Who knows if they will...
그럴지 누가 알겠어요...
The He family had just been acquitted. How dare you say that?
He 가족은 방금 무죄 판결을 받았습니다. 어떻게 감히 그런 말을 할 수 있나요?
Ren Yinxiao is my senior brother.
Ren Yinxiao는 나의 형입니다.
this is true.
이것은 사실이다.
All the more reason to avoid suspicion.
의심을 피해야 할 이유가 더욱 많아졌습니다.
You did contribute to resolving internal conflicts
내부갈등 해결에 기여하셨습니다 .
But this is a different time.
하지만 지금은 다르다.
But I am also from Jia Lin.
하지만 나도 Jia Lin 출신이에요.
Protect the people of Jia Lin , defend Jia Lin
Jia Lin의 사람들을 보호하고 Jia Lin을 보호하십시오.
It is the inherent responsibility of the He family.
이는 He 가족의 고유한 책임입니다.
I will never forget this.
나는 이것을 결코 잊지 않을 것입니다.
Your Majesty, don’t trust people gullibly.
폐하, 사람을 함부로 믿지 마십시오.
What happened with the Prince Regent should serve as a lesson.
프린스 섭정에게 일어난 일은 교훈이 될 것입니다.
Your Majesty, please think again.
폐하, 다시 생각해 보십시오.
Y'all shut up.
다들 닥쳐요
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
If we meet on the battlefield
전장에서 만나면
Do you really dare to confront Ren Yinxiao?
정말 감히 Ren Yinxiao와 맞설 수 있습니까 ?
My sword is always aimed at Jialin's enemies
내 검은 언제나 가림의 적을 겨냥하고 있어
And there will be no mercy.
그리고 자비는 없을 것입니다.
OK
좋아요
I agree with your request for a fight.
나는 당신의 싸움 요청에 동의합니다.
You will be the commander of our army.
당신은 우리 군대의 사령관이 될 것입니다.
Come with me to Nanjiang.
나와 함께 난장으로 가세요.
- Your Majesty. No. _ -No!
- 폐하. 아니요. _ -아니요!
Absolutely not! His Majesty!
절대적으로하지! 폐하!
Your Majesty, you cannot do this.
폐하, 이러시면 안 됩니다.
Absolutely not!
절대적으로하지!
why not?
왜 안 돼?
He Jiuling risked his life and brought me from the deep palace to this hall.
He Jiuling은 목숨을 걸고 나를 깊은 궁전에서 이 홀로 데려왔습니다.
She is more loyal than any of you.
그녀는 당신들 중 누구보다 충성스럽습니다.
Before returning to Beijing, she was the number one general in Nanjiang.
베이징으로 돌아오기 전 그녀는 난장(南江) 제1장군이었다.
Every time He Liang marched, she accompanied him.
He Liang이 행진할 때마다 그녀는 그와 동행했습니다.
With every win, her name appears on the report.
승리할 때마다 그녀의 이름이 보고서에 표시됩니다.
If anyone doubts her,
누구든지 그녀를 의심한다면,
Will be regarded as a remnant of the Jiang family.
장씨 가문의 잔재로 간주될 것이다.
Your Majesty, there has never been a female commander in history,
폐하, 역사상 여성 사령관은 없었습니다.
Not to mention fighting alongside the emperor.
황제와 함께 싸우는 것은 말할 것도 없습니다.
The master of Xingxiang Pavilion is here.
Xingxiang Pavilion의 주인이 여기에 있습니다.
Your Majesty.
폐하.
Your Majesty, it is risky to act rashly at this critical moment .
폐하, 이 중요한 순간에 경솔하게 행동하는 것은 위험합니다 .
Why not listen to Xingxiang Pavilion’s opinion?
Xingxiang Pavilion의 의견을 들어보는 것은 어떨까요?
Well, that's right.
글쎄요. 맞습니다.
Your Majesty.
폐하.
The result predicted by Rong Yu is
Rong Yu가 예측한 결과는 다음과 같습니다.
This journey is very dangerous. This is extremely ominous.
이 여행은 매우 위험합니다. 이것은 매우 불길한 일입니다.
This this……
이것저것…
So, as I said, the best plan right now is
그러니까 제가 말했듯이 지금 당장 가장 좋은 계획은
Withdraw troops and negotiate.
군대를 철수하고 협상하라.
but if we don't go
하지만 우리가 가지 않으면
The predicted outcome was no chance of survival.
예상된 결과는 생존 가능성이 없었습니다.
What should we do? This is a difficult decision.
우리는 무엇을 해야 합니까? 이것은 어려운 결정입니다.
Your Majesty, this...
폐하, 이...
This requires further discussion and consideration.
이를 위해서는 추가적인 논의와 고려가 필요합니다.
But it is absolutely impossible for He Jiuling to be the commander-in-chief .
그러나 허구령이 총사령관이 되는 것은 절대 불가능하다 .
If Xunnan knew about this,
만약 Xunnan이 이 사실을 알았다면,
They will laugh at us.
그들은 우리를 비웃을 것입니다.
If a woman can do it
여자가 할 수 있다면
What men can't do
남자들이 할 수 없는 일
Isn't this even more ridiculous for this man?
이 사람에게는 이것이 더 우스꽝스럽지 않습니까?
Incompetence is laughable.
무능함은 웃기다.
Incompetent, stubborn,
무능력하고, 고집이 세고,
and humiliate a woman
그리고 여자를 모욕한다
Ridiculous.
말도 안 되는.
am I wrong?
내가 잘못?
you
너
I have read so many books,
책을 너무 많이 읽었는데,
But it is not as good as the young master who has not entered the palace.
그러나 아직 왕궁에 들어가지 않은 젊은 스승만큼 좋지는 않습니다.
After hearing Rong Yu's words, He Jiuling
Rong Yu의 말을 듣고 He Jiuling은
Do you still dare to go?
아직도 감히 갈 수 있나요?
certainly.
틀림없이.
OK
좋아요
That's perfect.
저건 완벽 해.
Then I will let you become the real General He.
그러면 나는 당신을 진정한 장군으로 만들겠습니다.
This time, it's not you who protects me.
이번에는 나를 보호하는 것은 당신이 아닙니다.
But it's me, Xuanyuan Cheng'an,
하지만 나야, Xuanyuan Cheng'an
and you, He Jiuling,
그리고 당신, He Jiuling,
just like ancestors
조상들처럼
Xuanyuan, He family,
Xuanyuan, 허 가족,
Sharing life and death with each other.
삶과 죽음을 서로 나누는 것.
♫ Under the sunset♫
♫ 석양 아래♫
♫I have traveled thousands of miles♫
♫나는 수천 마일을 여행했습니다♫
♫Playing the piano under the moonlight♫
♫달빛 아래 피아노 연주♫
♫ Drinks won’t let me forget ♫
♫ 술은 내가 잊지 못하게 해줄 거예요 ♫
♫Write down what I miss you♫
♫내가 당신을 그리워하는 것을 적어보세요♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫우리의 운명은 종이에 적혀있습니다♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 가장 강한 포도주처럼 ♫
♫There is no escape from fate♫
♫운명에는 탈출구가 없다♫
♫Looking back, I see you waiting♫
♫돌아보면 기다리고 있는 네가 보여♫
♫Our life is full of joy and sadness♫
♫우리의 삶은 기쁨과 슬픔으로 가득 차 있습니다♫
♫ Longing to crystallize into a bright galaxy♫
♫ 밝은 은하계로 결정화되고 싶은 그리움 ♫
♫You turned around quietly and closed the marriage contract♫
♫당신은 조용히 돌아서서 결혼계약을 체결했습니다♫
♫Ask how many stars there are in the sky♫
♫하늘에 별이 몇 개 있는지 물어보세요♫
♫Write down what I miss you♫
♫내가 당신을 그리워하는 것을 적어보세요♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫우리의 운명은 종이에 적혀있습니다♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 가장 강한 포도주처럼 ♫
♫There is no escape from fate♫
♫운명에는 탈출구가 없다♫
♫Looking back, I see you waiting♫
♫돌아보면 기다리고 있는 네가 보여♫
♫Our life is full of joy and sadness♫
♫우리의 삶은 기쁨과 슬픔으로 가득 차 있습니다♫
♫ Longing to crystallize into a bright galaxy♫
♫ 밝은 은하계로 결정화되고 싶은 그리움 ♫
♫I play the piano gently, waiting for passers-by like you♫
♫나는 피아노를 부드럽게 연주하며 너 같은 지나가는 사람을 기다린다♫
♫It turns out that you are my inseparable destiny♫
♫당신은 나의 뗄래야 뗄 수 없는 운명이라는 것이 밝혀졌습니다♫